Lee:
The director tells us
you're running
an elite team.
-They're tested.
By me.
I want you all to meet
the newest member of your team.
Special Agent Mike McQuigg.
You're like
a bad country song.
No such thing.
Ryan: You remember
a few weeks ago
when Alex was in the hospital?
Don't ever do that again.
These kinds of things have
a way of infecting a unit.
Shelby: It's always
the one closest to you
holding the knife.
Just say it.
I kissed her.
♪♪
Gomez: Have you ever heard
the name "Elizabeth Nutting"?
Good morning to you. too.
Carmella.
She's a professor of nuclear
physics at Hudson University.
At 11:00 last night.
she walked into
the nuclear reactor on campus
and stole 10 pounds
of uranium 235.
Wow.
Any history of...
No. She's uncontroversial.
apolitical. no priors.
Nothing out of the ordinary.
Who else knows about this?
This is
Code Word clearance only.
Her co-workers
don't even know.
The NRC supervisor
discovered the uranium missing
this morning.
Checked surveillance.
which showed her putting
the lead box into a suitcase
and wheeling it
right out the door.
And how do we talk about it
with her colleagues?
You don't.
It's Saturday.
The facility is closed.
If anyone asks. you work
for the Nuclear
Regulatory Commission.
And. Owen. the Kashmir Summit
between India and Pakistan
is in town this weekend
at the Fairmark Hotel.
News media would be all over us
if they heard about this.
This is what
your black ops team is for.
Find Elizabeth Nutting.
find the uranium.
And I need an update from you
every two hours.
Understood.
♪♪
Alex: All right. so.
what do we think happened?
University salary.
husband's out of work.
kid's in private school.
Money is what happened.
She has a PhD in nuclear physics
from Stanford.
Yeah.
smart don't mean clean.
I agree.
Ted Kaczynski has a PhD in math.
H.H. Holmes was a doctor.
Ted Bundy went to law school.
Okay. but we have no evidence
that she's a psychopath.
"Saturday."
That's today.
Deep. call the loft.
See if Nick made it
to the doctor.
On it.
Okay. something
doesn't feel right.
No. it doesn't.
Why do I get a feeling
we're not talking about
this case anymore?
Ryan told me
what happened at the hospital.
You kissed my husband?
He kissed me.
And it was not returned.
You two
have a complicated history.
And that's exactly what it is.
Shelby.
History.
♪♪
Three plates.
They were all here.
They watched Prokofiev's
"Romeo and Juliet"
for three hours last night.
Doesn't sound like someone
planning a uranium heist.
does it?
No.
Well. they're definitely made
for each other.
What makes you say that?
Both professors.
both into books and art
and Prokofiev.
You know.
you and Shelby have that.
I told her.
How'd that go?
Hm.
♪♪
The kid's insulin kit.
They just left this behind?
They must have been
in a hurry.
Celine. go ahead.
Celine: The kid didn't show up
to the doctor's.
Her son is severely diabetic.
He's never missed
an appointment before.
Celine. she talk to anybody
on the phone last night?
There's nothing on her phone
records or her husband's.
♪♪
She's looking up
at the cameras.
She's scared.
Well...
she must have known that the FBI
would see this at some point.
She's looking at them.
Oh. who's them?
Good question.
She's doing this
under duress.
♪♪
What?
Doorbell camera.
[ Computer beeping.
keyboard clacks ]
What am I looking for?
Behavior.
Anything
out of the ordinary.
What is she doing?
Well. she's looking
through a stack of files.
Well. she's not looking
at the camera.
She's hiding something.
Wait. wait. wait. wait.
That -- That green folder
wasn't there before.
She left that there
on purpose.
All right.
Green folder.
Got it.
What is it?
Owen. it's --
it's a midterm exam.
and the student's name
is...Adnan Hamaja.
A-D-N-A-N H-A-M-A-J-A.
...A-J-A.
Got it.
Celine: I've located
the doorbell camera.
Tapping into
the neighbor's Wi-Fi system.
Adnan Hamaja -- He's a sophomore
at Hudson University.
A Pakistani national.
here on an F-1 Visa.
I'm in.
The cameras usually store about
24 hours' worth of footage.
Oh. my God.
You guys.
What?
♪♪
Freeze!
Rewind it.
Right there.
Tighter.
♪♪
We enhanced the image
from the door camera.
The van is a rental.
Rented
by another Pakistani national
by the name
of Fahad Harith.
Any known affiliations
with terrorist groups?
Damn it.
We don't know if it's official
Pakistani government or...
The president said no.
He said no?
Did you tell him
that an unprecedented attack
on the Kashmir Summit
is highly probably?
The summit is important
to the White House.
They don't want it derailed.
Has anyone explained to him
what a nuclear weapon
is capable of?
Careful. Owen.
Carmella. what's the plan?
You are the plan.
You will find
this Adnan Hamaja.
you will find Dr. Nutting
and her family.
and you will return
the uranium safely.
Understood?
Understood.
♪♪
All right.
The summit's
going ahead as planned.
Let me guess -- Gomez wants us
to move on the apartment.
You didn't tell Gomez that
a GPS chip in the rental van
led straight
to Adnan Hamaja's place?
Why the hell not?
Because she'd order an
immediate raid on the apartment.
We can't do that until we know
who's running this thing.
Because a sophomore in college
definitely is not.
So Alex. McQuigg. and Deep
have eyes on the apartment.
Celine:
You guys. we got a hit.
Elizabeth's son's
insulin prescription
was filled
at a Bronx pharmacy.
Bronx? Fine.
We'll head out there.
Uh. nope. Shelby. Ryan.
and Jocelyn will go.
Ryan can go with you.
We'll take Harry.
Why?
No reason.
Whatever's going on with
you two. home stays home.
Shelby. Ryan. and Jocelyn --
the pharmacy.
Harry. Celine -- with me.
♪♪
McQuigg:
What's taking him so long?
Alex:
Just give him a minute.
How are we doing. Deep?
Deep:
We?
Well. I am covered
in bugs and cold mud
while you guys
sit in a nice. warm van.
But it's worth it
to take down the Pakistanis.
Hey. don't make
this personal. okay?
Well. the Pakistanis
killed two of my uncles.
But you're right --
It's not personal at all.
You wouldn't understand. Alex.
It's a blood feud.
You're from Oakland.
Yeah. well. Oakland has
its own share of blood feuds.
All right. I'm in.
Do you have a picture?
Uh. twist it to the left.
Stop. stop.
You got it.
I see Adnan. the professor.
and a couple dudes
with big guns.
Where's
the husband and son?
Doesn't look like
they're in there.
What's he saying?
He's ordering food
for delivery.
Chicken tikka masala
and garlic naan.
Indian food.
Guess they don't hate
everything about you guys.
Okay. we got to figure out
if the uranium is in there.
Well. short of blasting
in there and asking 'em.
what's the plan?
I'm working on it.
♪♪
No pharmacy's
gonna let us take a look
at their surveillance footage
without a warrant.
Who doesn't have Wi-Fi
in 2018?
The Bronx.
♪♪
[ Man speaking indistinctly
on TV ]
♪♪
Oh!
So sorry.
Sorry! So --
I -- So sorry!
So sorry!
♪♪
Anything yet?
Come on. Elizabeth.
She's got this.
♪♪
Hey. hey. Elizabeth.
This is Alex Parrish
with the FBI.
We're watching.
Now. is the uranium
in the apartment?
Just nod
or shake your head.
♪♪
I'm recently pregnant.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Um. I'm a little embarrassed
to ask.
but I seem to be using the
restroom more often than normal.
Go ahead.
It's around the corner.
Thank you!
That is so kind of you.
Back there.
Thank you.
♪♪
Talk about what?
You know?
She won't even
acknowledge me.
I know I messed up. okay?
But everybody has baggage.
Everybody has a past.
♪♪
Nice job. Shel.
You have a signal?
♪♪
There.
I count one.
One in front
and one at the door.
We'll never get facial rec
off this image. though.
No. but at least
now we know
they're keeping the family
somewhere local.
They may be local.
but it's still a needle
in a Bronx haystack.
♪♪
[ Indistinct conversations.
elevator bell dings ]
This word "chatter." We don't
have a direct translation.
You know me
better than that. Druv.
and you know
what I'm asking.
You're Director General for
Indian Security for the summit.
Come on.
I haven't heard chatter.
But when it comes
to the Pakistanis.
90% of my job
is to expect trouble.
Have you asked the Pakistani
I.S.I. the same question?
Omar Sial is my next stop.
Just because he's state
security doesn't mean
he's not a terrorist.
♪♪
Harry?
How are you guys doing?
Harry: Yeah. good.
We've bugged every
single Pakistani guest
room in the building.
If they so much as sneeze.
we'll know.
This place
is crawling with spies.
What are we suppose to do
if something goes down?
Can't exactly stash a gun
in this outfit.
Well. no. yeah.
a gun's handy.
but there are other weapons
lying around.
It's a bit obvious.
but good.
What else?
Come on.
You must know
you can make sleeping gas
with the right combination
of bleach. soda.
and Worcestershire sauce.
Why do
we need sleeping gas?
We have you.
♪♪
Hello?
Hello?!
They -- They --
They took my family.
You --
You have to find them.
Alex: Elizabeth. we have
a team already searching.
Now. where is the uranium
in the apartment?
No! No!
You -- You can't come in here.
They'll kill them if I don't
help them make the bomb.
Please. please.
My son is only 6.
He -- He has d--
Diabetes.
Yes. we know.
We also know
he has insulin.
Oh. thank God!
Elizabeth. I need you
to be strong. okay?
We're gonna find them.
I promise.
Now. please. just tell me.
where is the uranium?
It's in
the living-room closet.
Oh! Aah!
Fahad: Back on the couch!
Now!
Okay. go.
We'll be in touch soon.
Oh.
♪♪
[ Keyboard clacks.
cellphone clicks ]
What are you doing?
I don't care what Owen says.
The uranium
is a game changer.
We got to get in there now.
I promised her.
Are you really willing
to risk thousands of lives
to save two?
You heard her.
There's no bomb yet.
You're guessing.
It's an educated guess.
I'm an educated redneck.
You know what that makes me?
A redneck.
You are not the kind of man
that would let a little kid die.
You have no idea
what kind of man I am.
Oh. yeah? You want to look
into my eyes and say it?
Say "I'm willing
to let that kid die."
♪♪
Fine.
If we're not storming
the gate.
then we got to make sure that
uranium never becomes a bomb.
Wait.
Why aren't
they making it into a bomb?
What are
they waiting for?
Deep: They're waiting
for a neutron initiator.
McQuigg:
You need a trigger.
It's a very sophisticated piece
of equipment.
They wouldn't have one
at Hudson University.
How do you know that?
Well...
Because it's illegal
to own one.
So they'd have
to smuggle it in.
Elizabeth. we need to know
when the neutron initiator
is arriving.
Do you know?
♪♪
Where is my family?
Do what you're told.
and you'll see them soon.
I always liked you. Adnan.
You were
one of my best students.
Why are you doing this?
This isn't you.
Who is making you do this?
Okay. Elizabeth.
Don't interrogate him.
Just find out when.
Just tell me
how much longer.
That's all I ask.
Stop talking.
Soon.
It will be today.
Nicely done. Elizabeth.
Very nice.
♪♪
Enough!
I told you to shut up!
Tell Owen the initiator's
already in New York.
♪♪
Wait. wait. wait.
Is there a...
Owen:
Omar Sial is a master spy.
Interpol has made a number
of terrorist allegations
against him.
but they never stuck.
You know why?
Diplomatic pouches?
Sovereign property.
It cannot be searched or
confiscated by law enforcement
for any reason.
He could smuggle anything
he wanted to in there.
Guns. weapons.
Ladies' underwear.
A neutron initiator.
So. has Deep told us what this
neutron initiator looks like?
Size of a flashlight
with wires coming out of it.
Okay.
Right. we'll look for it.
Listen to me closely.
Here's the rub.
If either of you
should be caught.
the FBI would have to disavow
any knowledge of you.
You can back out now.
Miss out on all the fun?
Not a chance.
I'm in.
You want me to make you
a neutron initiator?
Yeah.
but it shouldn't work.
Oh. it won't.
I don't like this idea
at all.
Is there any idea
you do like?
Generally. no.
♪♪
How's it looking down there.
Owen?
Finishing up his biryani.
Did he pair it
with the Sancerre rosé?
I hear it's delightful.
Just search the pouches
and get out. Harry.
Hello?
Room service.
♪♪
Oh. Found them.
Okay.
Right.
Papers. papers. papers...
Chewing tobacco.
Ah!
Elfkin monstrosities.
I mean. honestly.
where would you wear these?
Celine:
Any sign of the blasting cap?
Nope. nothing yet.
♪♪
Harry. Sial's leaving.
He's on his way
back upstairs.
I've got time.
He's leaving the elevator.
You need to get out now.
Just two more pouches.
15 seconds. Harry.
You cannot get caught.
No. still no sign
of the blasting...cap.
Oh. damn it.
This little...
Oh. no.
Little bugger won't close.
Harry. you need to move.
On it!
♪♪
Harry. what's going on?
Harry? Harry!
♪♪
Harry!
Yeah. All good.
I handled it.
Man: Don't move!
Owen. they have him.
As I said. the cells
are almost always isolated.
McQuigg: The operative word
being "almost."
What if there's a code word
you're supposed to say?
The blasting cap
is the code word.
I want to remind you
that the blasting cap
is made from an actual
flashlight. and it won't work.
Only Elizabeth will know that.
This is crazy.
Yeah. well. we're at crazy.
So buckle up.
Are you
the one assembling the device?
Then I suggest
we get to work.
I'm not doing anything
until I see my family alive.
You can kill me if you want.
I don't care.
Adnan: No!
If I let you talk to them.
will you build it?
♪♪
Oh. James. honey.
No!
Mommy!
Mommy?
Where are you?
Got it.
Hacked into his cell.
Is Nick okay?
Mommy. I'm scared!
Recording and transmitting.
Please. we need help.
You guys getting this?
We got it. McQuigg.
Mommy. I don't feel good.
Elizabeth: Hey. baby.
I'm so sorry.
Liz.
Nick needs more insulin.
No! No. no. no. no!
Please. no!
Wait. Freeze it.
No. no. Please.
N--
You see that?
Look behind him.
Blow it up.
Now let's look closer.
What do you see?
Are those tires?
Zoom in.
Not just tires.
Oversized.
Could be truck tires?
Well. I guess McQuigg
doesn't have the market cornered
on redneck.
Okay.
How many shops sell
specialty RV tires in the Bronx?
♪♪
Doesn't look like much
to me.
A bit more. you'd have enough
for another Hiroshima.
♪♪
Fahad: Who is it?
I have initiator.
Then who the hell are you?
♪♪
Adnan:
I asked you a question.
Who the hell are you?
♪♪
Elizabeth. get down!
McQuigg: Drop it!
Elizabeth: Oh!
♪♪
What do you think
you're doing. McQuigg?
Saving your life.
I had this under control.
You had three guns
in your face.
Drop it.
Kick it away.
Oh. please.
what is happening?
Have you found my family?
Are
They're gonna kill them.
Where the hell are they?
I don't know.
I swear.
But if we don't deliver
an active nuke to the drop-off
by 4:00 p.m...
they're dead.
Oh. no!
No.
Ryan: All right.
Three tire shops down.
four to go.
How ya doing up there. Shel?
You remember that
gun
Everything was going to plan.
We had the guns.
We had the money.
And that little rat-faced
informant blew our cover.
Oscar.
He was a moron.
So you stabbed the buyer
in the back with your high heel.
grabbed his gun.
and we ended up
shooting our way out.
I realized two things
that day.
One. that you and I
make one hell of a team.
And. two.
that I owed you my life.
♪♪
I never wanted to be
your backup plan.
It didn't mean anything.
Shelby.
If it didn't mean anything.
why did it take you two weeks
to tell me about it?
♪♪
I swear -- I don't know where
they're keeping her family.
Who's your contact?
Some Pakistani diplomat?
Damn it.
Not Pakistani.
This is a Rudraksha mala --
a Hindu rosary.
The last thing you'd find
on a Pakistani Muslim.
Isn't that right. Adnan?
I don't get it.
It's a false flag operation.
Indian nationalists
hoping to frame Pakistan
in a mushroom cloud.
It won't just scuttle
the peace talks.
It'll put America
on India's side forever.
That true?
You Indian?
You don't know what those pigs
have done to my family.
You don't know
what they're capable of.
But now we know
what you're capable of.
♪♪
Commander Sial.
Okay.
Sial: Owen.
I understand
there was an incident
in your hotel suite.
I'm sorry.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
But we did find
this communications device
in my hotel room.
Any idea
where it might have come from?
None.
♪♪
Celine.
Any sign of him?
No.
And the place is swarming
with Pakistani security.
♪♪
Does this look like
a real nuke?
Not really.
But if they don't know
what they're looking for.
it won't matter.
They're going to inspect it.
They'll know it's a fake.
Shut up.
No one's talking to you.
We're not gonna give them
the chance.
We're not delivering a nuke
to a bunch of terrorists.
Elizabeth: Yes. we are.
Alex: Elizabeth...
They still have my family.
Adnan is right.
If we don't deliver
a real bomb. they'll kill them.
No.
Don't.
I don't want
to hurt anyone.
but I know
how to use this.
Put the gun down.
Professor.
Elizabeth. I don't think
you're thinking straight.
Hand Adnan your gun.
Do it!
♪♪
Slowly.
You two do the same.
Do it.
♪♪
I'm going to attach
the real blasting cap.
Shoot them
if they try to stop me.
You can't set off a nuclear bomb
in New York City. Elizabeth.
Well. you're not gonna let
that happen.
And I'm not gonna let
my family die.
♪♪
[ Man speaking indistinctly
on TV ]
♪♪
[ Man speaking
in native language ]
Man:
How's the weather
in Islamabad?
Hot. I'm guessing.
[ Men shouting
in native language ]
♪♪
Excuse me.
Do you work here?
We're closed.
Dang it!
Look.
we're going on a road trip.
We could really use
a new set of tires.
Look. we could really use
some help. man.
I said "get lost."
Yeah.
♪♪
All right.
Got 'em.
♪♪
Adnan: Okay. stop.
Your father?
Is that why you're
doing this. Adnan?
The Pakistanis murdered him
when I was 7.
I'm sorry.
What happened?
I was playing football
with my friends.
My father was at home.
We all heard something.
and...
I remember thinking
it was fireworks.
When I got home...
it was all gone.
The house.
My father.
A Pakistani bomb.
You are willing to kill
thousands of innocent people.
put my family in danger.
because your father died?
You're one to talk.
You helped him deliver
a nuke to midtown Manhattan.
Alex: Okay.
Adnan.
you know this isn't gonna
bring your father back. right?
No.
But maybe
it will save someone else.
Hey.
Harry.
How'd I do. Coach?
Yeah. you did good.
Harry.
Alex and McQuigg are hostages
to Professor Nutting.
They're in the wind
with a nuke.
Sorry. I think
Celine's sleeping gas
has just affected
my hearing.
Did you say that Professor --
And the Pakistanis
aren't the bad guys anymore.
The Indians are.
I turn my back
for one minute. and...
Let's get moving.
I need to follow an old friend.
See where it leads.
♪♪
So. what's the plan?
Is this where you're meeting
your contact?
Shut up and walk.
♪♪
Man: Let's go.
Dad. what's happening?
It's okay. buddy.
Don't be afraid.
Move!
♪♪
McQuigg: Khatri.
Indian government
in the terrorism business now?
Indian. Government.
A contradiction in terms.
My country
no longer has the courage
to take real action
against its enemies.
You have your bomb.
Where is my family?
♪♪
Will it work?
It will do
what it's supposed to do.
Please. please.
I did my part.
Khatri.
You'll kill thousands
of innocent people.
"Innocent Americans."
Another contradiction in terms.
Please.
No! Oh!
Okay. okay.
Elizabeth.
I need you to stay calm.
Just. please.
Man:
♪♪
No.
Please.
♪♪
Follow me.
Come here.
♪♪
Shelby!
Aah!
♪♪
Ryan: You all right?
Yeah. You?
♪♪
It'll make things right.
After our deed here. the
Americans will side with India.
McQuigg. get down!
Get down!
♪♪
Hold your fire!
I think we're good.
♪♪
Owen.
Where's Adnan?
He's gone.
Yeah. and so is the bomb.
♪♪
Hey.
I see it.
The summit's
in the ballroom.
I'll go through here.
You go around.
Double back
if you don't find him.
Yeah.
♪♪
Adnan!
Stop.
Stop. stop!
Okay.
Please.
Put your gun down.
This doesn't make you
any better
than the people
that killed your father.
Who says I'm better?
They just need
to know how it feels.
I know.
I know. but...
Do you think your father
would have been proud of this?
♪♪
No.
I'm sorry.
♪♪
Thank you
for saving my family.
What you did today. Elizabeth.
was beyond reckless.
Do you see that?
You put thousands of lives
at risk.
I'm ready to accept
my punishment.
I'm just glad that my family
is alive and safe.
We brought your family here
to see you.
You --
You did that for me?
After everything I did?
No.
We did it for them.
♪♪
Sure. she put a lot of people
at risk. but...
Oh. my God.
Are you serious?
There's a "but"?
She thought
we had it covered.
And. really. what she traded
was 20 years with her family
in order to keep them safe.
You. of all people.
could understand that.
What do you mean?
Italy.
Andrea and Isabella.
Those are their names.
right?
You're not in prison.
but you left them
in order to keep 'em safe.
How do you know about them.
McQuigg?
Are you investigating me?
Investigating?
No.
Studying.
Well. don't.
♪♪
Hey.
Hi.
You okay?
I was sure
it was the Pakistanis.
But you were right --
I was making it personal.
Maybe.
But you also helped stop
a nuclear bomb
from exploding in the middle
of midtown Manhattan.
♪♪
You're lucky you're from
Oakland and not from Delhi.
You're not burdened
by the same history.
We're all burdened
by history. Deep.
Cheers.
♪♪
Ryan:
Paperwork's done.
You ready to go?
Mm-hmm.
♪♪
Hey.
You know why I didn't
tell you for two weeks?
Hmm?
It's 'cause I was terrified
of losing you.
You're not my backup plan.
Shelby Wyatt.
You're my only plan.
Is this the part
where you thank me
for saving your life again?
Oh. hell. yeah.
♪♪